SIBUSISO 'TITO' ZWANE

Front-end Developer

London, England, United Kingdom titozwane28@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ titozwane https://github.com/ PullingStrings

Skills

HTML/CSS
JavaScript
React
TypeScript
jQuery
Node.js
AWS, Google Cloud,
DigitalOcean
Git

Education

Full Stack Web
Development
Immersive , Full Stack
Web Developer

General Assembly

2017 - 2017

CTI Education Group
International Diploma in
Computer Sciences,
Computer and
Information Sciences
and Support Services
2008 - 2009

The Academy of Sound Engineering Engineer's Degree, Audio Engineering 2009 - 2011

PROFILE

A highly skilled front-end developer with over a decade of experience building custom websites and web applications. Specializing in React, TypeScript, HTML/CSS and JavaScript, I have worked with clients ranging from corporate banks and global law firms to art spaces and music projects. I am a natural problem solver that likes working in collaborative environments.

EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer
Cheil (Samsung Ltd)
London, UK — Oct 2020 - present

I currently work with different clients on different work streams for Samsung. Within these work streams, I develop and implement merchandising strategies for Samsung's MX pages, campaigns, launches, and promotions to drive sales and improve customer engagement. I also manage optimisation requests from IM divisions to improve the overall performance and user experience of Samsung's online platforms.

- Enhance Samsung.com UK experience through data-driven insights and user feedback.
- Develop and test potential solutions for business-oriented strategies
- Execute projects for MX (merchandising experience) pages, campaigns, launches, improvements, and offers.
- Manage optimisation requests from IM divisions.
- Design and develop custom full pages for Samsung's flagship smartphones.
- Collaborate with Cheil and SES team to deliver digital solutions and customer support.
- Develop tools and features for efficient management of Samsung UK's repair and support services.

Front-end developer

Freelance

London, UK — May 2020 - Oct 2020

Working with multiple clients to create and build their online businesses and organisations.

Tito's Wishlist

I am seeking a company with a strong culture, focused on making a positive social impact. I'm eager to work with modern JavaScript frameworks to further my skills. Working within diverse teams that encourage sociability and inclusivity across race and gender. Having the opportunity to contribute to both new and existing projects is always a significant advantage for me.

- Building and exporting legacy PHP websites to modern content management systems.
- Responsible for migrating MySQL databases and creating new responsive front-end interfaces.
- Designing and developing UI to fit business brand identity.
- Assist in managing website hosting including liaising with support remote teams to improve site speeds.

Web developer

Four Communications

London, UK — Oct 2018 - Mar 2020

- Built bespoke client websites, databases, and web applications for clients such as the Estèe Lauder Group, NHS, the Booker Prize, and the Home Office.
- Utilized HTML/CSS, JavaScript, PHP, JQuery, React, and TypeScript to produce interactive and database-driven sites- Deployed and maintained varied Cloud services including AWS, Google Cloud, and DigitalOcean
- Provided capacity building on built systems to enable easy use and maintenance by account teams, and contributed to digital strategy and technical build sessions
- Led client-facing technical development and guidance for solutions and products with suppliers and colleagues, and provided creative guidance to business pitches

Junior Software developer

Eventogy

Lonon, UK — Feb 2018 - Jun 2018

- Built a secure, cloud-based platform for corporate conferences and events management, aimed specifically at professional, legal, and finance industries
- Utilized HTML5, AngularJS, Express, Node.js, MongoDB, and Mongoose to build a scalable and audit-compliant platform for events executives

Web developer

General Assembly

London, UK — Jul 2017 - Nov 2017

- Completed an intensive three-month full-time program in Full Stack Web Development
- Built four web apps utilizing technologies such as ReactJS, Express, Node.js, AngularJS, MongoDB, and Mongoose